<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java | Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://avery7li.github.io/category/java/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://avery7li.github.io/category/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Java</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Zhengdan Li</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://avery7li.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Java</title>
      <link>https://avery7li.github.io/category/java/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Aid Match System</title>
      <link>https://avery7li.github.io/project/global-aid-match-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://avery7li.github.io/project/global-aid-match-system/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In summer 2019, I participated in the IBM Call for Code competition as a member of the Bank of China team. The competition looked for innovative ideas on disaster relief issues. We were tackling the inefficient relief supply distribution, a problem caused by the lack of transparent information and trust. When a natural disaster happens, information acquisition between two parties that need and provide resources rely on traditional media. There are often information barriers between each other that lack a resource scheduling scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;methods&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure mutual trust, blockchain was used in our solution as it has a transparent mechanism. Blockchain technology has the benefits of increased transparency in data shared on the network, contributing to enhanced trust among different organizations. During the development process, I used the Go language to implement chaincode, a “smart contract” that handled the demand and supply matching logic under the Hyperledger Fabric framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on blockchain, we built functions such as information release and evaluation systems. In addition, we formed the scheme of a matchmaking system to match the disaster-stricken party with the relief provider. The design also included a feedback mechanism for the participant organizations, and the results would affect the supply distribution priority of the next matchmaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;results&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the development and research of the Global Aim Match System, the team formed a systematic disaster relief chain solution that would increase transparency and boost the efficiency of disaster assistance. Our project placed among the top five in the Greater China region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.ibm.com/callforcode/solutions/2019-solutions/&#34;&gt;Call for Code 2019 Global Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars Game Center</title>
      <link>https://avery7li.github.io/project/mars-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://avery7li.github.io/project/mars-platform/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As a deliverable of the second-year software design course, I developed an open-source Android Game Platform that contains three games in a group of five members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;methods&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game center was developed on Android Studio using the Java programming language. In terms of the design, there are two classes important for the individual games. The first class is the board manager, which controls the behaviour of the boards. The second class is the movement controller that controls the behaviour of the grid views. The movement controller composites a board manager so that it supervises the manager according to the user’s interaction, such as tapping and swiping, to the grid views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game center has three core fragments, which are the profile fragment, the scoreboard fragment, and the games fragment respectively. The profile and scoreboard fragments store and display user information corresponding to data on the Firebase database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main design pattern used in the game center implementation is the Model-View-Controller pattern, where the model classes contain the data, view classes present the data and controller classes modify the data. With this design, the testing was convenient as only the controller (logic) classes need to be tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;results&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform contains registration, login, and scoreboard features, which allow the players to form communities, play new games, and compete in a ranking system. The sample games provided on the platform include Sudoku, 2048, and Sliding Tiles. The figures below show the game center preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:ssa-logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;login.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Login Page&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Login Page
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:ssa-logo1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Screenshots&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sudoku.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Screenshots&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Game Screenshots
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;growth&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this project, I learned and practiced object-oriented programming using Java. In addition, the Mars platform was my first large project in a team environment. The time our team spent working together at Bahen center was one of the best memories of my undergraduate. I learned from this experience that teamwork is much more than five individuals working in parallel like threads. Creative solutions often come from team interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
